可是要记住 你姓吉拉曼恩
But remember: You're a Kiramman.
我会带突击队去底城完成三项任务
I will lead a strike team into Zaun with three objectives:
找到金克丝
Locate Jinx,
摧毁微光
dismantle Shimmer,
铲除所有效忠于希尔科的残党余孽
and neutralize any agents still loyal to Silco.
裂沟工业的不断发展
The rise of industry in the fissures
也带来了越来越严重的毒气
has led to the air becoming increasingly toxic.
人们称之为“灰瘴”
They call it the Grey.
我已经着手派建筑师 设计了一套通风系统
I've instructed our architects to devise a ventilation system.
保证底城居民可以自由呼吸
The people of the underground deserve to breathe.
(金克丝)
人们称之为“灰瘴”
They call it the Grey.
《英雄联盟:双城之战》
第二季第三集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
谢谢 我以为我死定了
Thanks. I thought I was a goner.
你是史密奇的人
You're Smeech's man.
以前是
Was.
现在不是了 我叫西诺特
Not anymore. Name's Heenot.
我...
I...
感觉自己也是时候该退休了
Oh, I decided it was time for me to retire.
应该是有人想要让你退休吧
Looks more like someone decided to retire you.
也对 我最不擅长就是审时...
Yeah, well, timing was never my strong...
抱歉 不好意思
Sorry. Sorry, it's...
都是灰瘴 弄得我...
It's the Grey. It gives me the...
快说你是怎么进到这里的
Tell us how you wound up here.
等等
Hey, wait, wait.
是金克丝 要玩大的
Jinx is off the rails, even for her.
眼下她正在兴头儿上
She's got a real fire lit under her ass.
但这次真的有点太过了
She's planning something big,
她要对排风系统来个大改造
right here in the pipeworks.
这地方还挺大的 是吧
It's a pretty big place down here.
她往旧隧道那边去了
She was headed towards the old tunnels.
说是要给排风口改改道
Something about rerouting the vents.
原来如此
This is it, then.
- 铐上 - 为什么
Cuff him.
我该撂的都撂了
Hey, I told you everything I know.
可以算你是自首
You're a confessed criminal.
好好在监狱里面过退休生活吧
You'll spend your retirement in a cell.
检查装备
Check your gear.
平日的训练就为今天
This is what we've trained for.
能聊两句吗
Can I get a minute?
第一次拒绝见你是因为不感兴趣
Your first request for an audience was uninteresting.
第二次是因为觉得你不够格
The second, inappropriate for someone of your station.
第三次
The third...
是懒得搭理你
plain annoying.
平时换别人早死八百回了
People have lost their heads for less.
直说吧 阿玛拉
So tell me, Amara,
你这个皮尔特沃夫商会的人 想跟我谈什么
what does a member of Piltover's merchant guild want from me?
我不是为了商会的事来的
I'm not here representing the guild.
我是为了要追一笔债
I've come here to settle a debt.
管账的人在前厅呢
My bookkeeper is down the hall.
你偷走的东西
What you've stolen...
那可是千金难换的
...is more precious than any gold.
你真以为逃到皮尔特沃夫 就能摆脱我们了
Did you truly believe Piltover was beyond our reach?
我儿子已经死了
My son is dead.
难道他的死还不能让你们满足吗
Is that not enough to sate your bloodlust?
我可没把你当傻子看 安蓓萨
I haven't insulted your intelligence, Ambessa.
也请你别把我当傻子
Do not insult mine.
我们很清楚你在皮城想干什么
We know what you're chasing in Piltover.
我们不会让你得逞的
We will not allow it.
不让
Allow?
不劳大驾
Thank you.
你的到访倒是证实了我的猜测
Your visit only confirms my suspicions.
凭你个老巫婆还想阻止我
Try to stop me, insolent witch.
我的死活不重要
My death means nothing.
以前的恩怨 你早该放下了
You should have given up the feud.
你根本不懂家人对我来说意味着什么
You have no inkling what family is to me.
增加三倍守卫
Triple the guard.
这事儿不会就这么完了
This will have consequences.
控制权要赶紧拿下
We need control now.
萨罗还没准备好
Salo isn't ready.
是不是可以考虑把梅尔拉进来
Perhaps it's time we involved Mel.
不行
No.
必须跟她保持距离
We must distance ourselves.
做我们的敌人对她更安全
She's safer as our enemy.
萨罗我会摆平
I'll handle Salo.
这女的失踪的事瞒不了太久
Her disappearance won't go unnoticed for long.
我担心的不是这个
It's worse than that.
应该要让其他人按兵不动
We should cut the others loose.
听着 如果那个叫西诺特的 说的是真的
Listen, if that Heenot idiot is telling the truth,
那金克丝可是憋了个大招来对付我们
Jinx is gonna have surprises in store for us.
那更应该多带些人
All the more reason to bring backup.
只要察觉到他们的踪影
She'll smell their nerves a mile away
她就会利用这一点来对付我们
and find a way to use them against us.
我说得不对吗
Tell me I'm wrong.
这次我不能再让她逃掉了
I can't let her get away again.
- 你确定你准备好... - 我的妹妹
- Are you sure you're ready to...? - My sister is gone.
死了
她现在只是金克丝
There's only Jinx now.
这事儿也该了结了
It has to end.
你的母亲去世
I'm so sorry
我也很难过
about your mother.
很抱歉 我什么都做不了
I'm sorry I can't bring her back,
但是你能不能...
but please just...
我生命中的每个人都变了
Everyone in my life has changed.
但是我希望你不要变
Promise me you won't change.
不会的
I won't.
出去
Out.
你该知道在这儿找到你 并不是件难事吧
Do you realize how easy it was for me to track you down here?
毕竟是我的地方
Well, I do own the place.
我对你仁至义尽了
It's enough work propping you up
为你花了多少心思 下了多少功夫
without you dulling what few wits are left rattling around in there.
你脑子里有数
If you propped
是仁至义尽还是虚情假意啊
as well as you prod,
要不然我干嘛要在这儿费时又伤神的
maybe I'd have better uses for my time
坐等那个吉拉曼恩家的大小姐
than sitting around waiting for an update
在底城玩猫抓老鼠的最新战报
on Princess Kiramman's underground escapades.
即便她连金克丝的影儿都没见着
She's gotten no closer to Jinx.
也丝毫不影响她 成为大家眼中耀眼的新星
But that doesn't seem to steal the stars from anyone's eyes.
让一个小丫头在自己的地盘抢了风头
Perhaps if you hadn't let a child overpower you
又怪得了谁呢
in your own chamber.
那个小丫头没什么
It's not the girl.
人们相信她是冲着她的姓氏
It's the name. It bewitches people.
你应该很清楚
You should know.
不然你认为梅尔凭什么能...
Do you really think Mel could have succeeded--?
再敢说我家人一句试试
Never speak ill of my family.
你到底来干什么的
Why are you here?
来给你醒醒神
To sober you up.
恭喜你成功了
Mission accomplished.
是时候了
It's time.
尽力把能召集的家族全部都召集起来
Rally every house and family with even a modicum of influence.
你能办得到吧
Can you manage that?
等等 真的吗
Wait. For certain?
可以 没问题 照你说的办
Yes, of course. Whatever you need.
另外还有一件事
There is another matter,
就是你们商会的那个阿玛拉
concerning your guild merchant Amara.
好的
And, yes.
皇冠
Lift.
就是这样
Fantastic stuff.
我们又见面了 莱斯特
Good to see you again, Lest.
我不干了
I'm out.
对我来说监视一个 有怪癖的议员不是什么难事
Keeping an eye on a councilor with peculiar tastes doesn't rattle me.
不过那个女人...
But that woman...
你见到过我母亲
You met my mother?
她想干什么
What did she want?
不知道 我被赶出去了
I don't know. They kicked me out
什么都没有听到
before I could hear any of it.
听没听到 你我都很清楚
We both know you heard every word.
对不起 我真不能说
I'm sorry, but I really can't.
莱斯特 这件事至关重要
Lest, this is vitally important.
我必须知道
I need to know.
你的目标不是萨罗
This was never about Salo.
你在利用我去接近她
You're using me to get to her.
然后呢
And then what?
你事成之后会管我的死活吗
You take what you need, hang me out to dry? Hmm?
我就是牺牲品
I'm expendable?
不 没有人是牺牲品
No, no one is expendable.
我恰恰要避免这种事发生
That's what this is all about.
凡事一旦沾上我母亲 就都存在风险
Everything with my mother is a calculated risk.
我答应你护你周全
I'd love to promise your safety,
除此之外 我也无法再承诺其他的了
but I can't make any assurances other than this:
如果要是让我母亲得逞
If my mother gets what she wants,
整个城邦都会遭殃
the whole city will suffer.
而眼下可以阻止她的人
And right now you're the only one
也就只有你了
who can stand in her way.
他们要宣布什么重大决策
They're setting up some big announcement.
名门望族都会参与
All the who's who.
他们计划夺权 辅佐萨罗上位
Aiming to take over and put Salo in the hot seat, but...
不过谁在幕后操纵 大家都清楚
we know who's really pulling the strings.
还听见个名字 阿玛拉
I caught a name. Amara.
不知道你认不认识她
I don't know what you make of that.
给你 这是新配方 很受欢迎的
Here, brand-new cocktail. All the rage.
是用微光调配的
It's made with Shimmer.
会在身体上留下痕迹
Leaves traces on the body.
有了这个 你就能摆平萨罗了
That should be all you need to shut Salo down.
谢谢你
Thank you.
另外就是
For what it's worth...
你母亲就算再凶狠 也有忌惮的事情
dangerous as she is, your mother was spooked.
我能察觉到
I could smell it.
就像被逼到墙角的猫一样
Like a cat backed into a corner.
维克托曾推测
Viktor hypothesized
也许有一种叫做“狂野符文”的东西
that there may be something he called "wild runes."
当我们的世界与奥术世界相邻的时候
Patterns that occur naturally
这种符文就能自然产生
where the border between our world and the Arcane is thin.
很像你用在海克斯科技上的
Runes like the ones you use in Hextech.
这种狂野符文和那些有什么不一样
What's the difference between those and wild runes?
把书递给我
Pass me a tome.
我用你能够听懂的表达
I used words you understood
让你做出相应的行为
in order to elicit your action.
这就是海克斯科技符文
This is what Hextech runes are.
把书递给我
Pass me a tome.
看 你叹气了
There, you sighed. Still a kind of language.
这也算是一种表达
A sound,
无需文字的表达
but not words.
是原始的 自然的 这就是狂野符文
Something raw. Natural. That's wild runes.
奥术在大多数地方都处于休眠状态
Most places, the Arcane is dormant, but here and there, it's more active.
但在你我这里却异常混乱
Wild runes are...
就有点像是指纹
Sort of like its fingerprints.
没错
Exactly.
所以你是想说 我们树上出现了图案
So you're telling me that pattern is on my tree
是因为你们为了一己私欲 让奥术不爽了
because you pissed the Arcane off with all your demands?
我可不是这个...
That's-- That's not what I...
这小伙子没准说中了
Oh, the lad may be onto something.
有因必有果
Every action sparks
有果必有因
a reaction.
哎呀 没接住
Oh, ball sockets.
你觉得这是过度使用 海克斯科技造成的吗
Do you think this could actually be a result of overuse of Hextech?
说到法术创造奇迹这种事情
I've seen miracles spring from the hands
我也见识过不少
of mages many times,
不过大多数结局似乎都不怎么好
but so often, they turned to horrors.
究其原因
I'd always presumed
我一直觉得是因为人类 难以驾驭强大的力量所致的
it was due to mankind's... turbulent relationship with power.
但或许
But perhaps
真正的原因其实 来自于奥术自身的属性
it is a property of the Arcane itself.
多年来
We tested
我们在各种条件下测试海克斯科技
our Hextech under every conceivable condition for years.
如果真给什么地方带来了某些影响
If there's some reaction taking place,
那为什么以前一点迹象都没有
how come we've never seen any sign of it until now?
为什么又会出现在一棵树上
And why would it appear on a tree,
而且还在地下
deep underground?
您消息可靠
Your source panned out.
我已经查过了
I've confirmed
萨罗今天私下见了几个家族的成员
Salo met privately with members of several houses today.
我应该第一时间告诉您的
I should have been first to bring this to you.
我保证下次不会疏忽了
I promise I wouldn't have missed it.
他们真是好大的胆子
It's just such a bold move.
- 这个节骨眼上简直... - 愚蠢
- And at this moment, it's... - Foolish.
您的母亲自然不可能是愚蠢的
Of course, your mother is anything but a fool.
一定是我遗漏了什么线索
There must be an angle I'm missing.
那件事查得怎么样了
Did you look into the other matter?
关于您哥哥的死因
There's a rat's nest
目前掌握的线索还不是很明朗
of misinformation surrounding your brother's passing.
跟他有过交集的人 身上都看不出什么问题
Whomever he crossed knows how to cover their tracks.
不过他们似乎快要 把您母亲的财产全部转移走了
Moreover, they've managed to strip your mother of most of her holdings.
她无路可退了
She's desperate.
这样的话只会让她变得更加危险
Which makes her all the more dangerous.
我们现在该怎么办
What are we going to do?
把药剂师叫过来
Summon the apothecary.
让他帮我看看这个
I'll want his opinion of this.
再跟进一下阿玛拉那边
And check in on Amara.
这儿还是海克斯飞门吗
This is still part of the Hexgates?
我们现在少说也往地下降了60米了
We must be at least 200 feet below the surface.
整个结构就像一条通道
The entire structure is a channel,
将海克斯科技的能量聚成精密光束
focusing the Hextech energy into a precise beam.
凯特琳
Cait.
逮到机会你就...
If you see an opening...
直接开枪
take the shot.
蔚
Vi.
你对它的设计怎么这么了解
How do you know so much about its design?
大量的阅读和自己的推导
Read what I could, deduced what I couldn't.
不过没想到上城人会把 这么重要的东西放到地下
Plus, I didn't think the Topside would trust anything that important below the surface.
最起码海克斯宝石矩阵该被放在地上
I thought the gemstone mesh was installed aboveground.
矩阵的确是在地上
The mesh is aboveground,
但我们担心万一飞门超载
but we weren't sure what would happen if the gate overloaded,
于是就在底部安装了保险装置
so we installed a failsafe at the base.
所以万一有爆炸 也影响不到你们
So instead of it exploding in your neighborhood,
遭殃的只会是我们 对吧
it would blow up in ours.
这儿距离裂沟还远着呢
We're miles from the main fissures.
对 是还远着呢
These are the same utility ducts
但这些管道跟我们底城的 供水管道和通风管道是相连的
that carry our water and facilitate our ventilation.
这就是为什么我们的树会受到影响
That would explain it affecting the tree.
真不可思议
Inconceivable.
真是
You know,
嘴上说着我们应该同甘共苦
you say we should feel like we're all one people.
结果却成了一出事 就让我们底城人先顶着
But whenever it rains, we're the ones that get wet...
怎么回事
What the...?
金克丝
Jinx! Jinx! Jinx! Jinx!
可算把我名字叫对了
Finally got the name right.
为了找我 你还真是连个地缝都不放过呀
Guess there really isn't a crack in the earth where you won't find me.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
你还记得以前睡觉前
Don't you remember the old Janna bedtime stories
范德尔给我们讲过的迦娜的故事吗
Vander used to tell us?
矿工们被困在地下
Miners trapped underground.
呼吸越来越困难
Air running thin!
在这时
But then
吹风的女人从天而降
some wispy wind woman wafts
把大家都救了出来
to their rescue.
这么离谱的故事
Wild the kind
不过是人们窒息的时候安慰自己罢了
of crap people get up to when you choke them out.
我们借助灰瘴清空街上的人
We used the Grey to clear the streets.
是为了保证安全
To keep people safe.
“我们”
"We."
没想到我姐姐会披上上城那层皮
Never thought my sister would turn bluebelly.
没想到我妹妹会让 别的孩子也变成孤儿
Never thought mine would orphan kids.
那又怎么了
Ha! Why not?
我现在谁的也不欠
Done it to myself enough.
不过把我的照片贴得到处都是
But plastering my face all over
是不是想让别人替你干那些脏活儿
so someone else would do your dirty work?
还往空气里下毒是吧
Poisoning our air?
你也变了不少啊 姐姐
You've turned a leaf, sister.
我受够了
我不想再拿你的错误来惩罚自己I'm done blaming myself for your mistakes.
我不想骗自己你还是我的妹妹
Done pretending you're my sister.
你不是了
You're not.
是你杀了她
You killed her.
我不会再让你玷污我对她的回忆了
I'm not gonna let you stain her memory anymore.
那就阻止我
Then stop me.
反正我不管做什么
'Cause no matter what I do,
好像都死不了
I just can't seem to die.
对不起了
I'm sorry.
我也对不起了
I'm sorry too.
我就知道你们俩
I know you're sweet on her.
以后要是有机会
Hope you got a chance to, you know...
倒是可以...
Before...
动手吧
I'm ready.
那个是狂野符文吗
Is that a wild rune?
我也不知道它到底是什么
I have no idea what that is.
我们究竟做了什么
What have we done?
继续 来啊
Go on. I'm ready.
是你真好
I'm glad it's you.
就只能是你
Had to be you.
不要
No!
你干嘛
What are you...?
快放开我
Get off me.
快点让开
Get away from her.
- 凯特琳 - 让开
- Cait. - Move.
- 快点躲开 - 凯特琳 她只是个孩子
- Scram, kid. - Cait, she's a child.
让开 这回她逃不了了
Move. She's not getting away again.
凯特琳
Cait.
让开
Move.
凯特琳
Cait!
不 不应该是这样的
No, no, this isn't how it's supposed to...
快离开这儿
We have to go now!
凯特琳
Cait.
你居然拦我
You stopped me.
我不能看着你犯错
I shouldn't have had to.
我本来有机会的
I had the shot.
那只是个孩子 万一打偏了呢
That was a kid. What if you missed?
我怎么可能打偏
I wasn't going to miss.
你这是怎么了
What's wrong with you?
我一直告诉自己你们俩不一样
I keep telling myself that you're different.
可我错了
But you're not.
你们俩果然是姐妹
It's her blood in your veins.
那为什么你要像她一样呢
Then why are you the one acting like her?
依罗拉
Elora?
你怎么了
What's wrong?
黑色玫瑰
Black Rose.
感谢各位应邀齐聚这里
Thank you all for answering my summons.
我个人对安蓓萨米达尔达的 个人能力是十分钦佩的
I've come to trust the expertise of Ambessa Medarda.
她的名声有口皆碑
You no doubt recognize the name.
我刚刚从她那儿得到了 一些令人沮丧 遗憾
She's just shared with me some very upsetting,
又是意料之中的消息
but sadly unsurprising, news.
晚上好
Good evening.
昨天我与你们商会的阿玛拉见过一面
Yesterday I met with your guild merchant Amara.
商议如何重建城市
We spoke of rebuilding,
怎样让这座伟大的城市恢复往日辉煌
restoring this great city to its former glory,
就在这时
when
突然闯进来两个底城刺客
two Zaunite assassins fell upon us.
我尽力去救她
I tried to save her.
可她还是丧了命
But the blade pierced her heart.
怎么能任由刺客的刀悬在心头
Our families should not need fear an assassin's dagger
让大家夜不能寐呢
in the night.
是时候做个了结了
It's time to end this.
你们一次又一次给底城机会
You've given Zaun opportunity after opportunity
让他们弥补罪过
to repair their wrongs,
可结果又怎么样
and how have they answered?
一半的议员被杀了
Half your council is dead.
就连追思会也不放过
Your memorial is made a massacre.
简直不可饶恕
Well, no more.
血债必须要用血来偿还
Wrath must be met with wrath.
必须即刻昭告天下
You must declare martial law.
任命一位将军来统领
Appoint a general to lead
直到威胁解除
until this threat is vanquished.
这名将军必须有魄力应对底城的堕落
Someone who will not pale when faced with Zaun's degeneracy.
并且一定要坚定不移
Whose conviction never wavers.
他还应当是社会的栋梁
A pillar of your community
其家族始终拥护进步发展
whose house has always stood for progress.
并且还要善于运筹帷幄
Who may consider my experience
我以及我率领的 诺克萨斯部队都将听他调遣
and my entire detachment of Noxian soldiers at their disposal.
只有这样
Until all
才能确保所有人平安无事
our families are safe.
所以
Of course,
此等的重任 只能交给
I could only be referring to...
凯特琳吉拉曼恩
Caitlyn Kiramman.
为你儿子报仇
Vengeance for your son.
是你
It's you.
来吧 孩子
Come, child.
一定会还你母亲一个公道
Your mother will have justice.
我发誓
I swear it.
字幕翻译: 付博文 韩一旻